David Hernández Uriostegui

David Hernández Uriostegui

Email address: Dhdezu@ciencias.unam.mx

Phone number: +52 473 124 1727

GitHub: https://github.com/DavidHdezU/

Skills

Programming Languages

- Java / Python 1.5 Years
- C/C++ 1 year

Languages

- Spanish (Native)
- French
- English

Education

Universidad Nacional Autónoma de México / BS of Computer Science

August 2019 - June 2023 (Expected graduation date), Mexico City, Mexico

BS of Computer Science, Faculty of Science

GPA: 8.58/10

Experience

Cloud Coverage Index Reporter

Nov 2020 - Present, Mexico City

- A program that receives an image as input and calculates the Cloud Coverage Index from the image
- Use the OpenCV library to manipulate each pixel from its RGB components and thereby select which pixels can be considered as clouds using a binary mask
- It can also generate a black and white image to see how the selection of pixels was to obtain the final result
- **GitHub Repository:** https://github.com/DavidHdezU/Cloud-Cover-Index-Reportert

Wolfram Alpha Telegram Bot

Nov 2020 - Present, Mexico City

- A Telegram that makes queries to Wolfram Alpha in order to help me and some of my classmates complete our math homework
- Currently looking forward to do some upgrades to make the bot more user friendly and having other options apart from maths
- GitHub Repository: https://github.com/DavidHdezU/WolframTelegramBot

Weather Report CLI

October 2020, Mexico City

- Weather report is a CLI program used to obtain weather information from a given dataset of flight tickets.
- Use OpenWeatherMap API to make requests to get the data from each city in the datasets
- Use ThreadPoolExecutor (Python) to optimize the time execution, due to the limit rate from the API
- **GitHub Repository:** https://github.com/DavidHdezU/WeatherReport

Local Hack Day - Build/ Find me a pal

November 2019, Mexico City

- Part of the development team of a hackathon project (third place) to build a website, to help dogs in street situations and in kennels to find them a new home.
- Developed the HTML base files to build the website
- GitHub Repository: https://github.com/DavidHdezU/Local-Hack-Day

Introduction to CS Final Project / Chess Game

November 2019, Mexico City

- Developed from scratch a chess game to present as final project
- Used Java to program every class and Processing3 to create a GUI to play the game
- GitHub Repository: https://github.com/DavidHdezU/Java-_Chess

Summer of scientific research-Universidad de Guanajuato/ Darkogenesis

May 2018 - July 2018, León, Guanajuato

- Writed a theoretical physics research article about the relationship between baryonic asymmetry and the dark sector of the Universe.
- Article: http://www.jovenesenlaciencia.ugto.mx/index.php/jovenesenlaciencia/article/view/2520/pdf1

Awards

Participant at the 2019 UNAMxHacks Hackathon

Third place at Local Hack Day - Build 2019 (Mexico City)

About me

I consider myself as a very curious person, I enjoy researching and learning about new tech tools(and other stuff too) that can help me continue to develop my skills, and in that way help other people. I like reading and doing sports, I'm also very passionate about astronomy. I'm the kind of person that thinks that technology is the way that we allow the world to continue expanding his knowledge to keep creating and discovering new things that helps other people.